welcome back to am Northwest our next
guest is filled with fun facts about all
things vintage and he's here to share
another fun collection we welcome back
antique appraiser Gary gmer Gary thank
you thank you for having me oh my
goodness you brought some really
interesting things here I can't wait to hear
all about them it's the stuff you need
if you for a lady to put on her fancy
dresser table I love it I love it all
right so let's start with these over here
because these pieces are just stunning
aren't they fun yes if you want to feel
like you're you know a Spanish royalty
you need to have a a mirror frame and a
and a box like this for your dresser
glass beads it's just fun these were turn
of the century okay and uh
uh and and it they they were
made just strictly for you know utilitarian
and so but to made have that Moorish
Spanish look so you said a mirror would
go in here or this actually a picture
frame you could put a mirr in it
though absolutely and uh but it's a
how ornade it is isn't it yeah and you
can get all kinds of pieces that go with
it these kind of these are not part didn't
come with this but it's the same sort
of idea it's a little bit newer but uh
and then this was where you kept your
brush and your yeah or your yeah
buttons or jewelry or jewelry C
things like that would fit in there and
so around 1900 1920s that with this was
really popular and I mean still popular
today and and you can find it it's it
there the things like the picture frame
are a couple hundred bucks the box is
about 250 and everything so it's not
it's expensive but it's not Out Of Reach
kind of a thing you know that I love
that all right tell me about the perfume
bottles well the perfume bottle collection
came up from uh one collector and
this is only part of the ones we've been
dealing with but I thought they they
get a little bit of a variety um you know
the scent bottles like this these are
modern copies of old ones most of this
glass came these pieces the older ones
from late 19th early 20th century came
from checklist Sakia and that makes you
sound like you're really smart because
nearly all good glass came from checklist
lakia oh I didn't know that so for years
they had kind of the market for that
and they just kind of the different
styles I want to show you had the scent
bottles like this and the modern ones
aren't super expensive they're $5 or less
a piece silver overlay ones and
art glass ones silver overlay
that's actually where they cut it and
they fit it over it and um that was kind
of popular early 20th century as well
they run $150 range you know type that
but these atomizers aren't they
wonderful I love these absolutely
love these I mean I remember as a kid
seeing them in movies and thinking that
was the coolest thing yeah and they are
and you can and if you find them at a
state if you have one at your grandma's
or whatever this part you can get
replaced so these are all because they
they wear out they're rubber so you know
after 100 years they're not going to be
there right made by different companies
these is these are both from a company
called moer which again is a checklist of
v in company and you see there's cuz
they're so ornately painted and stuff then
these are real art deco ones I just
thought they were wonderful yes I love them
G that is so cool wow another category
of collecting perfume bottles if you want
to are the ones that were made by
specific companies for specific um uh
perfumes so bakara was was and and leik
are two the biggest ones these are the
ones we're talking about similar to these
These are this is leik and it was it
was made for a a particular originally
made for a particular perfume and so you
got this really expensive perfume in a
leik bottle so if you're go to an estate
look and see if it says leik you got
okay you're doing well on that and then
like this here is your master one that
would um little little uh Cask that would
work this way it opens see how well let
me break it here on television um has
your little stopper in it you see
my hand my hands were made for
this I got it so these this is actually
would be this would have perfume in it
would have perfume you have your stopper
and cover and uh it's just a little
different style it lay on this is in
the box but it would lay on your on your
dresser wow and that's a whole different
style per oh my gosh that is beautiful
so they've been making perfume bottles
for 6,000 years nearly and uh different
styles these are can I just show this one
too I know if you can see it very well
but look at this that's Sterling it's
Victorian probably 188 80 1870 1880 I
didn't look up the marks before I came
and you had three different kinds of
scents that you could have for your dresser
the three completely different kinds
aren't they fun I love it yes okay and
now yeah I have you have three different
pieces here that are stunning tell me
about these are these these called These
are called shatter Lanes which is I'm I'm
sure I'm slaughtering it it comes from
a French word that meant Lady of the
castle and the purpose of them was up until
about 1900 from the 1600s up to the 1900s
women didn't have pockets and so they
would have their their you know their
long skirts with the belt right this would
hook on if you look at the backside here
yeah it would slide down over the belt
and then you could have and so you have
this one here I I I think this one drats
from the early 1800s it probably was
silverplated at one time and this is a
utilitarian one this was a pencil the
pencil's not in there but it slides
forward this is a pin
here's your little your little scissors
oh my gosh carry your scissors thimble
and then this is you have your pencil
and this is what you would write on is
this piece here a little notepad and it's
Ivory and so you can use a pencil will
write on it you can rub it back off again
so you'd have that are you kidding me
yeah so this is what you they originally
would carry like Keys you know so they
that's why she was a lady of the castle
she could unlock the different doors cuz
she would carry the keys that way they
just didn't have a bag or purse or pocket
ET and this is what wow how much would
something like this cost well this is a
really cool one this is a probably and
in the condition it's in probably between
5 and 700 yeah wow um this one
is silver it's newer and this is
I think probably assembled because you
have a pill box you have a comb you have
a a glove hook a pencil and a stamp box
so you have some necessities and you
could trade out what you needed they had
formal ones which I didn't have one but
they have formal ones which were made of
gold sometimes made of silver that they
would wear it was proper to wear to like
a ball or a party this is crazy and you
would have your fan and you'd have your
eyeglasses and things like that on it so
and it wasn't until about 1900 after
1900 World War I era that they started um
carrying bags purses and had and because
women went to work and so they needed
clothed with pockets yes and wasn't
it that was we still need closed with
pockets yeah it is so we should always
have pockets if they ever change just see
me I can get you a shatter
Line This is a modern one I was going
to ask you one about one of the perfume
bottles do you remember like when Avon
used to do the perfume bottles and all
those it's kind that kind of reminds me
of that the figal pieces like that sure
sure they're they they did them for
a long time and now um as far as
collectibility go it dropped way off you
know when they when they Mass produce
them there it's not really collectible
is it it isn't and but now they're fun
and and people the kids are starting to
re uh discover some of these things a
little bit the prices aren't what they
used to be yeah but uh there is much more
of an interest to it so Gary this was a
blast thank you so much all right I've
got to use this I know